Tristan Jagan

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

tristan.jgn@gmail.com 647-863-6332 <u>tristanjagan.dev</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/tristanjagan</u> <u>github.com/TristanJgn</u>

PROFILE

While having had great experiences through my co-op program in accounting & finance, challenging myself and learning more everyday is what excites me. This motivated me to explore my long-standing interest in software development. Through my personal projects and BrainStation's Software Engineering bootcamp, I am ready to make the transition into a field that will challenge me, require me to be a lifelong learner, and enable me to solve problems.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MySQL, SASS, Agile, Web & REST APIs, Axios, User Authentication, GitHub

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering JAN 2023 - APR 2023 TORONTO, ON

University of Waterloo | Bachelor of Accounting & Financial Management SEP 2018 - DEC 2022 WATERLOO. ON

 Dean's Honours, President's Scholarship of Distinction

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, Software Engineering | BrainStation

APR 2023 - JUNE 2023, TORONTO, ON

- Conducted code review, grading, and provided feedback on weekly assignments for a cohort of 26 students
- Reinforced student learning by leading technical whiteboarding challenges, quizzes, daily and weekly check-ins, and review sessions
- Offered personalized mentorship and guidance on a 1-on-1 basis to each student in order to support and enhance their development

Investment Analyst, Venture Capital (Co-op) | Manulife Investment Management

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022, TORONTO, ON

- Engaged in pitch meetings with prospective B2B
 Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) startups and venture capital funds
- Performed in-depth diligence on existing portfolio companies and 17 potential investment opportunities
- Prepared investment memos analyzing go-to-market strategy, founding team capabilities, total addressable market, performance metrics, deal sourcing networks, competitive landscape, ESG policies, and precedent transactions

Investment Banking Analyst, Global Mining & Metals (Co-op) | National Bank Financial (NBF)

JAN 2022 - APR 2022, TORONTO, ON

- Provided financial advisory to strategic clients on sell-side mandates, buy-side processes, and formal valuations
- Managed internal databases including comparable companies, precedents, discounts, and price forecasts
- Sell-side advisor to Nomad Royalty on potential sale (EV: C\$750M+)

PROJECTS

Creator | Portfolio Sphere

APR 2023, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE PROJECT

- Created to help investors keep track of all of their holdings in one place
- Full-stack application featuring user authentication, password hashing, and automatic fetching of real-time data every 5 minutes from external API
- Tech stack: React, SASS, Axios, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL

Lead Developer | Industry Project

MAR 2023, BRAINSTATION CROSS DISCIPLINE HACKATHON

- Led two UX/UI designers, one data scientist, and one software engineer to create an innovative online grocery solution for Loblaws Digital in 24 hours
- Built out functionality for users to view and add items to cart, checkout, and be given recommendations for similar items based on their recent order
- Tech stack: JavaScript, React, SASS, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL